Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation Collection RG.001
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
Guide to the Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation Collection, 1916-1962
RG.001
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
11.5 Cubic feet 27 boxes and 2 bound volumes
The Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation (KME) was an integral part of the manufacturing industry in the United States in the early twentieth century. Keller machines created in the original factory on the Brooklyn waterfront were purchased by companies in Philadelphia, Upstate New York, Detroit, and England. By 1940, the company merged with Pratt & Whitney and moved to a new state-of-the-art complex in Connecticut. Although KME developed many products, the typical Keller machine was a tracer-controlled, horizontal milling machine, which duplicated molds and dies. The design of the tracer distinguished Keller from other milling machines because it allowed greater precision of patterns and therefore more accurate stamping and forging dies or casting molds. Eventually the automated tracer mechanism gave way to Keller machines with computer numerical control (CNC). Keller machines were essential to the early automotive and aeronautics industries and their design laid the groundwork for modern CAD/CAM (computer aided design/computer aided manufacturing) machines.
Many of the items in the collection sustained water and mold damage. The affected items were cleaned and encapsulated in archival polyester L-sleeves. Although safe for general use, those with severe allergies or respiratory diseases should handle with caution.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was donated to the Polytechnic Institute of New York University Archives by the children of Richard D. Keller in 2007.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement note
Series are arranged by format type. Arrangement within series is either chronological, by photograph number (which is largely chronological), or by subject.
Scope and Contents note
The Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation Collection includes company records, operating manuals, notebooks, scrapbooks, photographs, sketches, blueprints, publications, advertisements, newspaper clippings, ephemera, and product samples from 1916 to 1962. Due to preservation concerns, some materials were removed from their original housing. This is noted in the finding aid and, when possible, notebook and photo album covers were encapsulated and separated, but retained in the collection. If photographs were removed from an album or scrapbook, the original layout of the photographs is noted.
This collection documents machines and products of the Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation (KME) during its peak production years. Through the engineering innovations of the Sydney and Joseph Keller and their partner, John C. Shaw, the company, which began as an engraving shop in the late 19th century, grew to become an integral part of the twentieth century manufacturing industry. As KME produced newer, faster, and larger tool and die machines, the product line expanded from silverware to granite facades to automobile and aircraft parts. As KME's reputation grew, Keller machines were sold to factories in Philadelphia, Upstate New York, Detroit, and England. Mirroring the trajectory of many early twentieth century factories on the Brooklyn waterfront, KME eventually moved to a larger plant in Connecticut and merged with the Pratt & Whitney Company.
Biographical/Historical note
In 1896, Sidney A. Keller and Joseph F. Keller went into the business of designing and manufacturing dies for the silverware industry in New York. Since there were no American-made machines that were sufficiently accurate to make such dies, the small Keller shop used engraving and reducing machines that had been made in Europe. Joseph Keller, a mechanical engineer, eventually constructed machines for their own use.
As the business broadened and prospered, the Kellers recognized a market for small forging dies as well as silverware dies. Joseph designed and built a one-to-one duplicating machine and also a weight-controlled machine for the duplication of forging dies. This machine was designated the E-1 Automatic Die Cutter Machine.
The Keller plant in Brooklyn, located at 70 Washington Street, thrived as customers became interested in purchasing Keller-built machines. As a result, the Keller Mechanical Engraving Company became machine tool builders, and changed the company name to the Keller Mechanical Engineering Company (KME). The first machine was sold to Crescent Tool Company in 1915. Shortly thereafter, orders for reducing machines (Type D) were received from Remington Arms in Ilion, New York, International Silver Company, and other silverware manufacturing companies.
In 1916, the mechanical engineer John C. Shaw joined KME. His experience with building mechanical-electrical valve control machines gave him the idea for a Keller machine with electrical tool control. Shaw's idea was put on hold while KME joined the war effort to make airplane propellers. After the Armistice, Shaw set to work; by 1920 he had completed designs for the first Electric Tracer Control Keller Machine – Type BG 1. The first machine, serial #550, was shipped to the Budd Company in Philadelphia in March, 1921, and the second machine was shipped in July of the same year.
The popular BG 1 was followed by larger BG machines. Machines larger than 6’ x 4’ were designated BG 2s, and even larger still was the BG 3. The BG machines were followed by the BL machine. An electric tracer was also developed for the E Type machine, and similar electric controls were developed for use on lathes, planers and other machines. By the time it was purchased by Pratt & Whitney Company, Inc. of West Hartford, CT (P&W) in 1930, KME had sold and shipped over 4,000 machines. By then "Kellering" had become a common verb in the tool and die industry.
KME produced a wide variety of burrs made of high-speed steel for use in Kellering machines. In a similar manner, it was recognized that nearly all the operations performed on Keller Automatic Milling Machines required the use of either ball nose or radius end mills. It followed that customers using such a machine had to have a quick and convenient way to resharpen and grind their cutters. Recognizing this need, KME developed the Keller Cutter and Radius Grinder. Modifications of this machine were later sold by P&W as welcome companion pieces for the Keller BL and BG type machines.
By the 1940s, design responsibility for the Keller line passed to J. J. Jaeger, then Chief Engineer and later President of P&W. Two of Sidney A. Keller’s sons joined P&W: Alexander S. Keller as Vice President and Richard D. Keller, a graduate of Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute, as head of Sales for the Keller Division. Other members of the original Keller sales force at P&W were Paul Renno and Harry Reichert.
In 1954, P&W became part of the Penn-Texas Corp., assembled by German-born financier Leopold Silberstein, who hoped to make it part of a vast industrial empire. Soon after, Alfons Landa wrested control of P&W from Silberstein and used the company to seize control of old-line machinery manufacturer Fairbanks Morse, changing the name to Fairbanks Whitney. Boardroom battles ensued to determine who would head the company as it went into the red. Ultimately Pratt & Whitney and the Keller Division was absorbed into Colt Industries, which signaled the end of what was once one of the most prominent tool and die companies in the United States.
Source: The above is an abbreviated version of Peter Keller's history of the Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation. For the full historical note consult the on-site finding aid
Sponsor Note
This project was made possible in part by a grant from the Documentary Heritage Program of the New York State Archives, a program of the State Education Department.
Hale, Frank W.; Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation.; Keller, Joseph F.; Keller, Richard D., 1908-2003; Keller, Sydney A.; Polytechnic Institute of New York.; Pratt & Whitney Company.; von Braun, Wernher, 1912-1977; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Engineering; Machinery industry; Tool and die industry
- Series I: Records and Operating Manuals, 1921-1962; 3 boxes (11.5" x 15" x 3") and one bound volume
  Scope and Contents note
  These reports and instruction manuals cover Keller machines created by the Keller Mechanical Engineering Company and the Pratt & Whitney Division, Niles-Bement-Pond Company. Many of the items are contained in original company notebooks. Some notebooks were fashioned together for personal use and contain loose papers and blueprints.
  Keller machines described in the reports and manuals from the Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation include: the Type E Keller Automatic Die Cutting Machine, Type E-53 Keller Automatic Die Cutting Machine, Type E-63 Keller Automatic Die Cutting Machine, and Keller Automatic Mold Cutting Machine #543, Type BL, E-5, and E-6 machines and the Keller Lathe Control.
  The notebooks from Pratt & Whitney include Sales Department photographs and descriptions of Keller machines. Numeric Keller Machines, Keller Automatic CAM Milling Machines, BL, and BG-21 Machines are described.
  The Record Book contains a list of photographs arranged by photograph number with a description and date of the image. The photographs listed in the Record Book correspond to loose photographs and photographs in unpublished and published scrapbooks, notebooks, and manuals throughout the collection.
  Some notebooks in this subseries sustained water damage. Although problems such as cover dies bleeding and some stuck photographs with cracking emulsion are present, the damage is minimal. No mold was present during the time of processing.
  - Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation Records, 1921-1962 (Box 1)
  - Pratt & Whitney Division Records, 1937-1960 (Box 2)
  - Richard D. Keller's Operating Manuals, undated (Box 3)
  - Record Book, 1921-1962 (Object Bound volume)
- Series II: Notebooks, 20th century; 10 letter-size manuscript boxes
  The Precision Machine Tools Notebook contains catalogs, photographs, reports, and specifications of Keller GG, BG, BF, and E machines. Also included are descriptions, diagrams, and photographs of Keller machines equipped with "Right and Left" fixutres, the Keller CAM Milling Machine, and the Keller Automatic Bottle Mold Cutting Machine.
  The Keller Sales Department notebook contains sales brochures, photographs, blueprints, typed descriptions, and hand-written notes of Keller products arranged under the tabs: Aircraft, Blanking, Forging, Forming, Pattern, General, Two-Template Jig Bore, and Special.
  The three G.I. Notebooks contain photographs, diagrams, descriptions, and hand-written annotations on three Keller machines: BL3620 3-Spindle #M-1701, BG-3 #M-1721, and #M-1739 Model D.
  Many notebooks in the collection sustained water damage and mold infestation. When notebook materials are in a letter-size manuscript box, it indicats the original notebook was badly damaged and discarded. The photograph pages within each notebook were cleaned of mold and housed in polyester L-sleeves. Although safe for general use, those with severe allergies or respiratory diseases should handle with caution.
  - Subseries A: Keller BL Machines (Notebook #2), 1948-1961
    - Overall Views: Lot 3 Machine, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Overall Views: Line drawings, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Overall Views: Wood model of 20' x 7' machine, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Overall Views: 20' x 7' machine, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Overall Views: Single spindle machine with Weldment type angle fixture, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Overall Views: Special tilt head, photos #K-5581 to K-5597, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Overall Views: Special tilt head, photos #K-5598 to K-5628, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Overall Views: Lifting bed and swivel head, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Overall Views: Instruction book photos, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Overall Views: Static control cabinet and 3-spindle machine for BG-22, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Column base casting, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Lot 3 machine, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Vertical and horizontal gear boxes, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Gib adjustments, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Spindle attachment, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Section of column, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Tracer units, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Oiling system for vertical slide, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Spindle speed selectors, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Chip conveyor and bin, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Control unit, lead screw, and gear box, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Right angle spindle, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Sub-Assemblies: 3-Spindle machine, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Sub-Assemblies: High speed spindle attachment, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Tracers, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Depth indicators, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Splash guard, control panel, gear box, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Parts of M-1735 machines, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Right angle spindle head, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Sub-Assemblies: BG-22 gib locations, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Sub-Assemblies: BG-22 Installation, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Sub-Assemblies: Photographs for instruction, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Sub-Assemblies: BG-22 machine in crate, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Subseries B: Keller BG-22 Machines, Work Shots (Notebook #3), 1948-1965
    - Automobile parts produced in Chicago and Detroit, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - BG-22 Forging cut, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - BG-22 machines in England, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Work shot for Jarecki Machine Tool Co., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Work shots for Grunman Aircraft and Alfred Herbert Ltd., England, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Work shots for Wyman-Gordon, 1951-1953 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kellering an aircraft forging die for Wyman-Gordon, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Cover photo of "Canadian Machinery," Nov. 1951 (BG-22 machine in Canadian plant) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Automobile top panel coming off the press, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Work shots for Douglas Aircraft, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Kellering an auto body die: Budd, Philadelphia, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Photo used in "Modern Industrial Press," June 1953: Two BG machines in Ford's Buffalo Stamping Plant, NY (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Work shots for Alexson, Los Angeles, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Kellering aircraft parts, Detroit Kellering, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Kellering an aircraft part, Canadian Ltd., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Scenes from Keller film: Budd, Philadelphia, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Kellering aluminum, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Kellering at Sterling Engineering, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Kellering a fiberglass boat mold R.H. Freitag Mfg. Co., Akron, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Work shots for Willy's Motors, Richmond Division, California, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Kellering a Corvette body for Chevrolet, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - BG-22 applications for Alcoa, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - BG-22 applications for Cleveland Pneumatic Co., 1956 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Keller machines at Pressed Steel Co., England, 1956-1959 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Misc. BG-22 machines, 1957-1965 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Subseries C: Keller BL Machines (Notebook #5), 1947-1963
    - Overall Views, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Sub-contract Work, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 3-Spindle BL Machine, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 8-Spindle Duplicator, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Kellering Toilet Dies, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Kellering Granite, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Kellering Windshield, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Kellering Forging Die, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Kellering and Die for Turbine Blade Tooling, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Drawing Die and Other Work for United Aircraft, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kellering Misc., 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Plastic mold for Blower Housing, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Aircraft Prototype Fitting Hinge, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Oil Well Drill Point Forging Die, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Scissor Dies, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Silverware Dies, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Hughes Aircraft Hollywood Gun Shop, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Misc. Work Shots and Controls, 1948-1962 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Loose, Unlabeled Drawings and Photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Subseries D: Keller BL Notebooks: Sub-Assemblies (Notebook #5), 1948-1960
    - BL Sub-Assemblies: General photographs, 1948-1959 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Skids for BL machines, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - BL Machine lifts, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Right angle spindle and tracer bracket for Wheland Co., 1952 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 3-Spindle BL machine parts for Springfield Armory, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 2-Template attachment and shank holding fixture, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Control panels and cabinets, 1951-1960 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Electrical components, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Locating the transverse position of a tracer, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - BL-3620 parts for Ford Motor Co., 1956 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - BL-Machine gib locations, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Tracers for BL machines, 1951-1958 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Model C, Machine # M-1739: Tracer controlled machine, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Model C, Machine # M-1739: Views of the new BL machine, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Model C, Machine # M-1739: Slinging, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Model C, Machine # M-1739: Control cabinet, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Model C, Machine # M-1739: 3-spindle, single spindle, and vertical template attachment, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Model C, BL-3622: Overall views, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Model C, BL-3622: Sub-assemblies, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Model C, BL-3622: Electronic controls, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Model C, BL-3622: Placement on a skid, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Subseries E: Keller BL Machines, Work Shots (Notebook #6), 1941-1960
    - Machine # M-1710, 1956-1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Machine # M-1739, 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 3-Spindle BL Machine, 1941-1952 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kellering Granite, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Kellering Glass, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Kellering Plastic, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Aviation: Various Customers, 1949-1954 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Aviation: Pratt & Whitney Aircraft, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Aviation Parts and Dies for Sterling Engineering, 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Work Shots for Conn. Kellering Co., 1956 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Work Shots for Sales Dept., 1957 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Test Pieces, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Dies, 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sub-Contract Work, Tracer, and Profiling Job, 1948-1953 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Subseries F: Keller Machines Notebook (Blue), 1960s
    - Tab 1: General Machine Production, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Tab 2: 3-Dimensional, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Tab 3: Profiling, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Tab 4: Special Attachment Large Machines, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Automatic Duplicating Machine, 1950s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries G: Precision Machine Tools Notebook, undated
    - Precision Machine Tools Notebook Part 1 of 2, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Precision Machine Tools Notebook Part 2 of 2, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Subseries H: Keller Sales Department, Hartford, Conn. Notebook, undated
    - Keller Sales Department: Aircraft, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Keller Sales Department: Blanking, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Keller Sales Department: Forging, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Keller Sales Department: Forming, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Keller Sales Department: Pattern, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Keller Sales Department: General, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Keller Sales Department: Two-template jig bore, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Keller Sales Department: Special, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Subseries I: G.I. File Notebooks, 1934-1960
    - BL3620 3-Spdle M1710, 1941-1953 (Box 11)
    - BG-3 M1721, 1934-1945 (Box 11)
    - M1739 Mod. "D" Job Pictures 3-D, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
    - Keller Sales Department: Duplicating Machine Photographs, 1951-1956 (Box 11)
- Series III: Scrapbooks, 20th century; 1 letter-size manuscript box and 8 deep lid print boxes (14.5” x 18.5” x 3”)
  The Green Scrapbooks contain photographs with record numbers pasted to paper pages. For photo description, refer to the Record Book and search by record number.
  The photographs in the Pratt & Whitney Photography Department scrapbook were originally adhered to glue contact sheets with platic covers. The photographs were removed from the album and placed into acid-free folders as a preservation measure. Slips of paper in each folder show the original layout of the photos in the album.
  - Subseries A: Pratt & Whitney Photography Department, 1960s [?]
    - Page 1, recto (K-6979 -- K-6983, K-6987) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Page 1, verso (K-7007, K-7010) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Page 2, recto (K-6986, K-6900 -- K-6902, K-6985, K-6999) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Page 2, verso (K-6978, K-6984, K-6993, K-7016) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Page 3, recto (K-7011 -- K-7015, K-7017) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Page 3, verso (K-7018 -- K-7023) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Page 4, recto (K-6887, K-6903, K-6904) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Page 4, verso (K-7006, K-7008) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Page 5, recto (K-6988, K-6989, K-6995 -- K-6998) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Page 5, verso (K-7005, K-7009) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Page 6, recto (K-6736, K-6737, K-6990 -- K-6992, K-6994) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Page 6, verso (K-7112 -- K-7118) (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Page 7, recto (K-6905, K-6906) (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Page 8, recto (K-6710 -- K-6713) (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Page 8, verso (K-6820 -- K-6822, K-6852, K-6853, K-6888) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Page 9, recto (K-6889 -- K-6894) (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Page 9, verso (K-6912 -- K-6918) (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Page 10, recto (K-6921 -- K-6926) (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Page 10, verso (K-5919, K-6920, K-6927 -- K-6929, K-6931) (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Page 11, recto (K-6930, K-6932, K-6933, K-6935 -- K-6937) (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Page 11, verso (K-6938 -- K-6940, K-6942, K-6944, K-6945) (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Page 12, recto (K-6941, K-6943, K-7177 -- K-7181) (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Page 12, verso (K-7103 -- K-7108) (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Page 13, recto (K-7119 -- K-7123) (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Page 14, recto (K-6519, K-6614, K-6615, K-7095 -- K-7098) (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Page 15, recto (K-7159, K-7160, K-7162 -- K-7165) (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Page 15, verso (K-7161, K-7166 -- K-7168) (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Subseries B: Green Scrapbooks, 1931-1962
    - Photographs #2251 - #2684, 1931-1936 (Box 13)
    - Photographs #3862 - #4182, 1949-1951 (Box 14)
    - Photographs #4183 - #4503, 1951-1953 (Box 15)
    - Photographs #4504 - #4787, 1953-1954 (Box 16)
    - Photographs #4788 - #5070, 1954-1955 (Box 17)
    - Photographs #5071 - #5350, 1955-1957 (Box 18)
    - Photographs #5351 - #5888, 1957-1959 (Box 19)